

STEVE MAGUIRE

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

stevemaguire.dev || github.com/Zdeevo

I have recently completed an intensive 12 week software development course, learning all the fundamentals of web development while establishing a solid best practice approach.

The strong technical skills that I have developed during this course are supported and enhanced by the well-established transferable skills I bring from my previous roles. I am always seeking to strengthen and expand my skills through research and training, and I am always keen to engage with new and interesting ways to solve problems.

RELEVANT SKILLS

<u>September 2020 - November 2020 (12 weeks - full time)</u> Nology.io - Software Development course (remote)

An intensive and engaging 12 week programme learning the basics of software development, with a focus on web development.

Through my personal and client focused projects I have worked hard to understand these new skills within the context of my existing skill-base, and have enjoyed and appreciated every moment, no matter how challenging. I have been pushed to my limits by elements of the process, and I have realized that with a balance of self-belief, determination and teamwork I can push past those limits and succeed.

- Fundamentals: HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js and Git.
- Data management: Firebase, MongoDB
- **Personal projects** including a 'choose your own adventure' game, a searchable website utilising data taken from Punk API and a personalised cocktail database using MongoDB, all of which are hosted on my own portfolio site (see above).
- Client project: DADA app a parenting support & advice app for fathers with young children. Includes user access and authentication, mixed content handling and utilises Firebase for content management. Acted as product manager for the initial setup and first milestone update to the client.

EDUCATION

2005 - 2009

B.Sc. (Hons) Conservation Biology (with sandwich year)

University of the West of England, Bristol

2004 - 2005

B.Sc. Extended Science Foundation Year

Cornwall College Camborne (University of Plymouth), Camborne

<u> 1991- 1993</u>

BTEC OND Mechanical, Electrical and Electronic Engineering

Castlereagh College of Further and Higher Education, Belfast

BACKGROUND

My previous experience in senior positions allows me to quickly establish myself as both a team leader and a team member when appropriate. I have participated in all aspects of the roles I have held from simple manual work, through to full project management. I pride myself on my ability to ensure client/project needs are met whilst maintaining a strong team based approach supported by a robust yet adaptable skill set.

EMPLOYMENT

January 2016 - August 2020

Nicholas Pearson Associates (NPA) Ltd - Senior Ecologist (consultancy)

My position as senior ecologist in the ecology team at NPA required the following:

- Provision of landscape and sector specific advice, experience and expertise to projects as required, especially in specialist
- Project management: including project team identification and management, project programme agreement and tracking, budget management and project quality control;
- Production of surveys, site reports, licence applications, graphical and textual documents as appropriate, including QA of documents to ensure they met professional and company standards;
- Contributed towards the development and education of staff by delivery of training and advice; and
- Production of internal technical presentations ('tech talks'), as well as technical support to the team and wider company including tailored app development (with in-house IT team) and technical equipment advice, procurement and maintenance.

May 2010 - 2015

Simecology Ltd - Ecologist/Senior Ecologist (consultancy)

Ecologist/Senior Ecologist (May 2010 - 2015): Working both in a sub-contracted (as Greenbank Ecology 2010/11) and fully contracted capacity on commercial projects involving a variety of protected species. Roles included field surveys, report writing, team lead, ecological clerk of works and project management. (2014 - 2015) Along with these roles I was jointly responsible for the day to day running of the consultancy working closely with the Director/Principal Ecologist. In this role I engaged with all aspects of the business at a senior level.

August 2007 - 2012

Avon Wildlife Trust - Volunteer (Biodiversity Team): Worked full time for 10 months on a university placement year then continued as a regular volunteer and volunteer team leader.

OTHER

May 1993 November 1999	-	Capital Alarms	Senior engineer: Installation and maintenance of security systems including CCTV. Left to travel for 6 months.
April 2000 November 2003	-	Helen's Bay Organic Gardens	All aspects of growing, packing and delivering organic vegetables including customer liaison and budgeting. Managed a partner small-holding for one of those years. Left to live in Oregon, USA for 6 months with my partner.
Various		Other short term, part time work such as Care Assistant and Beach Cleaner (Cornwall during studies) and Joiners mate (US). I have also spent a total of 12 months travelling throughout India, where I met my partner.	

CPD/TRAINING/CERTIFICATION

- Ecology: Attended regular CPD events, expanding my skill set in areas such as protected species management and mitigation, use of camera traps to support research as well asbestos awareness, working at heights and other relevant safety training. I have also held survey/research licences for a number of protected species since 2009, as well as being registered on the Construction Skills Certification Scheme since 2010.
- Tech: Completed PfCO course and successfully achieved UAV pilot registration from the Civil Aviation Authority.

PERSONAL

I am a big fan of the new maker movement, and enjoy repairing and repurposing old or broken electronic equipment. I have built a bar-top arcade as well as assembled my own 3D printer and I am teaching myself Fusion 360 CAD/CAM design software. I have always been a strong believer in the use of technology to support and enhance our lives, and this course has given me the opportunity to manifest that belief in what I do going forward. I have balanced this course with a full home life, having two high school age children and a partner working full-time, as well as a very demanding half-husky dog!